{
  "q1": [
    {
      "question": "Karl Jaspers (pr. YOS-perz) is often called a Christian philosopher within this framework.\nThis philosophy was dubbed \"a humanism\" in a book by one of its major exponents, who also\nwrote Roads to Freedom. For 10 points, identify this philosophy originated by Soren\nKierkegaard and popularized by Jean-Paul Sartre (pr. SART) in which humans must create\nmeaning in the universe.",
      "answer": [
        "existentialism",
        "existential"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Southern supporters of this man launched racist attacks on his opponent by claiming that this\nman's rival danced with Mary Booze. This man became president of the firm constructing the\nEmpire State Building after losing the 1928 Presidential election to Herbert Hoover. For 10\npoints, name this \"Happy Warrior,\" the first major-party Catholic candidate.",
      "answer": [
        "Al Smith",
        "Smith"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "A work about these people is divided into sections concerning “History,” “Psychology,” and “Biology”\nand argues that these people have become a passive “Other.” One philosopher distinguished these people\nfrom barbarians and the uneducated to argue for their suffrage. J.S. Mill wrote about the Subjection of,\nfor ten points, name what group of people, the subjects of Simone Beauvoir’s The Second Sex?",
      "answer": "women"
    },
    {
      "question": "Margaret Thatcher claimed to have carried a copy of this man’s most famous work in her handbag\nat all times. This thinker rejects the “benevolence of the butcher, baker, and brewer” as the reason that\ndinner is expected and, in his most famous work, describes a metaphor about the unintended social\nbenefits of private, selfish actions as the “invisible hand.” For ten points, name this Scottish “Father of\nEconomics,” the author of The Wealth of Nations.",
      "answer": [
        "Adam Smith",
        "Smith"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "The production of this item names a group of 18th century nationalist revolutionaries in Italy.\nDuring the Industrial Revolution, the complete deforestation of Britain may have been prevented when\nblacksmiths replaced this item with coke. A companion company founded by Henry Ford produced this\ngood out of byproducts from its car manufacturing; that company is now called Kingsford. For ten points,\nname this hot-burning, wood-based, solid carbon fuel, commonly used in blacksmith forges and barbecue\ngrills.",
      "answer": "charcoal"
    },
    {
      "question": "Hermogenes recounts this man’s desire to die relatively young in order to escape the afflictions of old\nage in an account of this man’s Apology by Xenophon. This husband of Xanthippe was put to death by\nan Athenian tribunal by drinking hemlock on charges of corrupting the youth. For ten points, name this\nclassical philosopher whose namesake “method” employs rigorous questioning and who mentored Plato.",
      "answer": "Socrates"
    },
    {
      "question": "In 1639, Queen Christina of Sweden invited this thinker to organize an academy of science and to tutor her. One of his major works is presented as the product of six days thinking in solitude. This thinker argued that the soul was in the pineal gland as part of his theory of mind-body dualism, which he explored in part of his Meditations on First Philosophy. For ten points, name this philosopher whose Discourse on Method includes the concept “I think, therefore I am.”",
      "answer": "Ren´e Descartes"
    },
    {
      "question": "This leader tasked Lot Smith to form a militia and eliminate the Timpanogos. The proposed state of “Deseret” was spearheaded by this man, who lost much of his national credibility following the Mountain Meadows Massacre. This leader banned black men in his clergy, claiming they were sons of Cain. This man took control of a religious group after its founder died in Illinois. The Mormons were led to Utah by, for ten points, what successor of Joseph Smith?",
      "answer": "Brigham Young"
    },
    {
      "question": "Walter Kauffman’s biography of this man argued that syphilis caused his end of life madness, which seemingly began with an 1889 incident in which he rushed to save a horse from being beaten on the streets of Turin. This thinker, who stated that the “abyss will gaze back into you” in Beyond Good and Evil, discussed the role of the Apollonian and the Dionysian in his The Birth of Tragedy. Nazi German philosophy was heavily influenced by, for ten points, what German author of Thus Spake Zarathustra?",
      "answer": "Frederich Nietzsche"
    },
    {
      "question": "This Englishman’s belief that government must maintain “life, liberty, and estate” was echoed by Thomas Jefferson. He believed that the mind was born without any pre-established ideas, his “tabula rasa.” That concept was discussed in An Essay Concerning Human Understanding. He’s not Rousseau, but this philosopher argued for a social contract in another of his most famous works. For ten points, F name this philosopher and author of Two Treatises of Government.",
      "answer": "John Locke"
    },
    {
      "question": "This thinker claimed that human motivation was divided between eros and thanatos, or the life and death drives. This man divided the title constructs into manifest and latent content in his The Interpretation of Dreams. This thinker divided the unconscious into the ego, superego, and the id. Controversially claiming that young men develop an Oedipal [[ED- ih-\"pull\"]] complex, for ten points, which Austrian psychologist is considered the father of psychoanalysis?",
      "answer": "Sigmund Freud or Sigismund Schlomo Freud"
    }
  ],
  "q2": [
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "This language was used to write The Incoherence of the Philosophers, which was rebutted\nwith The Incoherence of the Incoherence. This was the language used by the medieval\nphilosopher Averroes (pr. AA-vuh-ROE-ez) and other writers based at Córdoba (pr. COREdoh-buh). For 10 points, name this language through which many Greek and Latin texts passed\nto Europe.",
        "answer": "Arabic"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "Which other Semitic language, which was the language which Jesus spoke, was\nfeatured in the Mel Gibson directed film, The Passion of the Christ?",
        "answer": "Aramaic"
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "A major advance in this field was formulated by Stanley Jevons and William Marshall in the\n1880s. This field's dominant textbook in postwar America was written by Paul Samuelson, who\nsubscribed to the ideas formulated by John Maynard Keynes. For 10 points, name this social\nscience which uses supply and demand curves to study financial decision-making.",
        "answer": "economics"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "Keynes's The Economic Consequences of the Peace warned that the World War I\nreparations payments imposed on what country were too harsh?",
        "answer": [
          "Germany",
          "Weimar Republic"
        ]
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "This man noted that “The clock cannot be set back. You cannot restore Central Europe to 1870” in\na work that lamented Clemenceau’s “Carthaginian Peace.” This author of The Economic Consequences\nof the Peace argued that natural business cycles should be moderated by government intervention. For\nten points, name this British economist who outlined modern macroeconomics with his General Theory\nof Employment, Interest, and Money.",
        "answer": [
          "John Maynard Keynes",
          "Keynes"
        ]
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "This New York Times columnist and modern Keynesian thinker won the 2008 Economics Nobel\nPrize as his theories of international trade were being tested in the recovery from the Great Recession.",
        "answer": [
          "Paul Krugman",
          "Krugman"
        ]
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "This philosopher became disillusioned with his former employer after watching him get distracted by eighty dancing girls at his court. This man’s concept of ren, or humaneness, exemplifies itself as compassion in the just man and society. A series of “Four Books” espousing this man’s thought was compiled by Zhu Xi [j-oo she] during the 1100s. This man’s sayings are collected in works such as the Analects. For ten points, name this ancient Chinese philosopher.",
        "answer": [
          "Confucius",
          "Kong Zi"
        ]
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "Confucianism was one of this many apocryphal “schools of thought” that flourished during the Spring and Autumn and Warring States periods. A 1956 political liberalization movement in China called for letting this many “flowers bloom.”",
        "answer": [
          "100",
          "one hundred"
        ]
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "This man’s The Practice and Theory of Bolshevism reflected his disappointment with the Soviet Union after a 1920 visit, which included a meeting with Lenin. This proponent of logical atomism supervised Ludwig Wittgenstein’s Ph.D. thesis. This philosopher’s namesake “teapot” is often used to shift the burden of proof in religious debates. With Alfred North Whitehead, this philosopher attempted to synthesize the foundations of mathematics in 1910. For ten points, name this British philosopher, the co-author of Principia Mathematica.",
        "answer": "Bertrand Russell"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "Bertrand Russell co-wrote a political manifesto with Albert Einstein concerning this subject in 1955. Treaties concerning this subject included SALT I, SALT II, and START.",
        "answer": [
          "nuclear weapons",
          "answers about nuclear proliferation, nuclear weapon testing, nuclear warfare, etc.",
          "specific types of nuclear weapons"
        ]
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "Averroes’ works are primarily commentaries on this philosopher, who originated the syllogism form for logical deductions and postulated the state of “eudaemonia” as the goal of human life. In a book named after this man’s son Nichomachus, this man advocated finding the mean between extremes as virtuous. The Lyceum was founded by, for ten points, what ancient Greek philosopher who was a student of Plato?",
        "answer": "Aristotle"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "Aristotle originated this philosophical discipline with a work of the same name. It inquires into the nature of being and existence as such rather than the particular properties of things that exist.",
        "answer": "Metaphysics"
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "This man’s last words noted that a rooster was owed to Asclepius, after this man’s prior refusal to save himself served as the basis for the dialogue “Crito.” This man, who described himself as a “gadfly,” was depicted by Jacques-Louis David drinking hemlock shortly after he faced trial for corrupting the youth of Athens. For ten points, name this philosopher, the teacher of Plato, who quoted this man in his Apology saying, “the unexamined life is not worth living.”",
        "answer": "Socrates R"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "In Plato’s Apology, a story is told that this oracle, the high priestess of the Temple of Apollo, said that there was no one wiser than Socrates.",
        "answer": [
          "Oracle of Delphi",
          "Pythia"
        ]
      }
    }
  ],
  "q3": [],
  "q4": []
}